在本讲座中，我们将继续讨论图像处理
In this lecture we're going to continue an earlier discussion about image processing
并学习一些有趣且有用的先进技术。图像处理
and pick up on a couple of more advance techniques that are interesting and useful. Image processing
是一个非常巨大的领域。
is a really huge area.
有一些大量的教科书可以很详细地介绍它。更多细节和
There are some massive textbooks that cover it in a lot of detail. Much more detail and
比我希望在这里做的更多。但我想向您介绍几种技巧
than I can hope to do here. But I want to just introduce you to a couple of techniques
我认为真的很有用。
that I think really are useful.
我们要揭示的第一件事是数学形态学。我们离开的地方
The first thing we going to reveal is the mathematical morphology. And where we left
它，我们可以使用形状滤镜，可以检测不同的正方形或矩形
it, we could use shape filters that could detect squares or rectangles of different
大小。在这里，我们将扩展它并看看我们如何检测可能的形状
sizes. Here we going to extend that and look at how we can detect shapes that are perhaps
对角线或圆圈。
diagonal lines or circles.
我们要访问的第二种技术是我们所谓的图像变形。这是公平的
The second technique we are going to visit is what we call image warping. This is a fairly
一般技术，允许我们改变图像的形状，我们将去
general technique that allows us to change the shape of an image and we are going to
看看我们如何使图像更大或更小的一些例子，关于我们如何做到
look at some examples about how we can make an image larger or smaller, about how we can
旋转图像或我们如何移动图像。
rotate an image or about how we can shift an image.